Guide to the Rice University School of Social Sciences, 2000-2019 UA 420
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas
Rice University School of Social Sciences records
2000-2019
Woodson Research Center, Rice University, Houston, Texas https://library.rice.edu/woodson
Birenbaum, Lisa
UA 420
10 Linear Feet 10 boxes
This collection includes annual reports (2001-2005), deans' strategic plans (2006-2007), external reviews (2008-2013) of the Departments of Political Science, Sociology, Economics, Anthropology, and Psychology, department records (1993-2007), and personnel files (restricted).
Biographical / Historical
Established in 1979 with 37 full-time faculty, forty years later the School of Social Sciences employed 97 full-time faculty in seven departments: Anthropology, Economics, Linguistics, Political Science, Psychological Sciences, Sociology, and Sport Management, all but the last offering doctoral degrees. Professional master's degrees are offered in Energy Economics, Global Affairs, Human-Computer Interactions and Human Factors, and Social Policy Evaluation. Allied centers: Douglas S. Harlan Program in State Elections, Campaigns and Politics, Hobby Center for the Study of Texas, Houston Education Research Consortium, Kinder Institute for Urban Research, Shell Center for Sustainability, Social Sciences Research Institute, and Texas Policy Lab. Approximately one-third of Rice undergraduates have a Social Sciences major and can take advantage of the Gateway Program, providing travel grants and opportunities to network and practice with professionals in their fields. Because of the nature of the School's patterns of instruction and research, faculty and students have a particular interest in current and public events, issues, and politics, publishing and commenting widely in various media. Since 1982 the School has hosted the annual Houston Area Survey..
Scope and Contents
This collection includes annual reports (2001-2005), deans' strategic plans (2006-2007), external reviews (2008-2013) of the Departments of Political Science, Sociology, Economics, Anthropology, and Psychology, department records (1993-2007), and personnel files (restricted).
Conditions Governing Access
Stored offsite at the Library Service Center and require 24-hour notice for retrieval. Please contact the Woodson Research Center at 713-348-2586 or woodson@rice.edu for more information.
Access Restrictions
This collection is open for research except for the Personnel Records series, which is restricted. These records require permission from the Dean of the School of Social Sciences for access. Contact woodson@rice.edu for assistance in making this request.
Arrangement
The materials in this collection have been arranged in four series as follows:
Series I: School of Social Science Records; Series II: Department Records; Series III: Personnel Records (restricted); Series IV: Addenda
Related Materials
See also UA 393 (Rice University Shell Center for Sustainability records), UA 347 (Rice University Department of Psychology records), and the collections of individual faculty members.
Index Terms
Subjects
Education; Psychology; Economics; Anthropology; Political science; Sociology; Universities and colleges
Subjects (Persons)
Birenbaum, Lisa
- Series I: School of Social Science Records, 1999-2013
  - Annual Report, 2001 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 1)
  - Annual Report, 2001, (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 2)
  - Annual Report, 2001 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 3)
  - Annual Report, 2002 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 4)
  - Annual Report, 2002 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 5)
  - Annual Report, 2002 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 6)
  - Annual Report, 2003 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 7)
  - Annual Report, 2003 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 8)
  - Annual Report, 2003 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 9)
  - Annual Report, 2004 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 10)
  - Annual Report, 2004 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 11)
  - Annual Report, 2004 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 12)
  - Annual Report, 2005 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 13)
  - Annual Report, 2005 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 14)
  - Strategic Plan, 2006 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 15)
  - Strategic Plan, 2006 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 16)
  - Strategic Plan, 2006 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 17)
  - Strategic Plan, 2007 (Box 1, Folder 18)
  - Global Health Minor, 2002-2007 (Box 1, Folder 19)
  - Alkek Fund for Neurosciences, 1999-2001 (Box 1, Folder 20)
  - External Review, Political Science, 2008 (1 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 21)
  - External Review, Political Science, 2008 (2 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 22)
  - External Review, Political Science, 2008 (3 of 3) (Box 1, Folder 23)
  - External Review, Sociology, 2009 (Box 1, Folder 24)
  - External Review, Economics, 2010 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 25)
  - External Review, Economics, 2010 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 26)
  - External Review, Anthropology, 2010 (Box 1, Folder 27)
  - External Review, Psychology, 2013 (1 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 28)
  - External Review, Psychology, 2013 (2 of 2) (Box 1, Folder 29)
- Series II: Department Records
  - Anthropology, 1998-2002 (Box 2, Folder 1)
  - Anthropology, 2003-2005 (Box 2, Folder 2)
  - Anthropology, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 3)
  - Economics, 1993-2002 (Box 2, Folder 4)
  - Economics, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 5)
  - Economics, 2005 (Box 2, Folder 6)
  - Economics, 2006-2007 (Box 2, Folder 7)
  - Political Science, 1995-2000 (Box 2, Folder 8)
  - Political Science, 2001-2002 (Box 2, Folder 9)
  - Political Science, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 10)
  - Political Science, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 11)
  - Psychology, 1996-1999 (Box 2, Folder 12)
  - Psychology, 2000 (Box 2, Folder 13)
  - Psychology, 2001 (Box 2, Folder 14)
  - Psychology, 2002 (Box 2, Folder 15)
  - Psychology, 2003-2004 (Box 2, Folder 16)
  - Psychology, 2005-2006 (Box 2, Folder 17)
  - Psychology, 2007 (Box 2, Folder 18)
  - Sociology, 2000-2003 (Box 2, Folder 19)
  - Sociology, 2004-2006 (Box 2, Folder 20)
- Series III: Personnel Records (restricted)
  - A (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Ba (Box 3, Folder 2)
  - Bea-Bej (Box 3, Folder 3)
  - Ben (Box 3, Folder 4)
  - Ber-Bi (Box 3, Folder 5)
  - Bl (Box 3, Folder 6)
  - Bo (Box 3, Folder 7)
  - Bra (Box 3, Folder 8)
  - Bre (Box 3, Folder 9)
  - Bri (Box 3, Folder 10)
  - Brown, D. (Box 3, Folder 11)
  - Brown, L. (Box 3, Folder 12)
  - Bry (Box 3, Folder 13)
  - Burg (Box 3, Folder 14)
  - Burn-Bust (Box 3, Folder 15)
  - Ca (Box 4, Folder 1)
  - Ce (Box 4, Folder 2)
  - Chae (Box 4, Folder 3)
  - Chan (Box 4, Folder 4)
  - Cor (Box 4, Folder 5)
  - Cu (Box 4, Folder 6)
  - Da (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 7)
  - Da (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 8)
  - De (Box 4, Folder 9)
  - Di (Box 4, Folder 10)
  - Do (Box 4, Folder 11)
  - Ec (Box 4, Folder 12)
  - Em (1 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 13)
  - Em (2 of 2) (Box 4, Folder 14)
  - Es (Box 4, Folder 15)
  - Fe (Box 4, Folder 16)
  - Fu (Box 4, Folder 17)
  - Ga (Box 5, Folder 1)
  - Gr (Box 5, Folder 2)
  - Ha (Box 5, Folder 3)
  - Ho (Box 5, Folder 4)
  - Hud (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 5)
  - Hud (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 6)
  - I-Ja (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 7)
  - I-Ja (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 8)
  - Jo-Ki (Box 5, Folder 9)
  - Kl-Ko (1 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 10)
  - Kl-Ko (2 of 2) (Box 5, Folder 11)
  - Lan (Box 5, Folder 12)
  - Lau (Box 5, Folder 13)
  - Lee (Box 5, Folder 14)
  - Li (Box 6, Folder 1)
  - Log (Box 6, Folder 2)
  - Long (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 3)
  - Long (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 4)
  - Lu (Box 6, Folder 5)
  - Mara (Box 6, Folder 6)
  - Marc (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 7)
  - Marc (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 8)
  - Martel-Martin, L. (Box 6, Folder 9)
  - Martin, W. (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 10)
  - Martin, W. (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 11)
  - McC (Box 6, Folder 12)
  - Mcl (1 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 13)
  - Mcl (2 of 2) (Box 6, Folder 14)
  - McL (Box 6, Folder 15)
  - Me (Box 6, Folder 16)
  - Mie (Box 7, Folder 1)
  - Mil (Box 7, Folder 2)
  - Mor (Box 7, Folder 3)
  - Mot (Box 7, Folder 4)
  - Mou (Box 7, Folder 5)
  - Murd (Box 7, Folder 6)
  - Murp-Mut (Box 7, Folder 7)
  - Nal (Box 7, Folder 8)
  - Nar (Box 7, Folder 9)
  - Ni (Box 7, Folder 10)
  - No (Box 7, Folder 11)
  - O'C (Box 7, Folder 12)
  - Oh (Box 7, Folder 13)
  - Osh (Box 7, Folder 14)
  - Ost (Box 7, Folder 15)
  - Pa (Box 8, Folder 1)
  - Ph (Box 8, Folder 2)
  - Pi-Pol (Box 8, Folder 3)
  - Pom-Pos (Box 8, Folder 4)
  - Pot (Box 8, Folder 5)
  - Q (Box 8, Folder 6)
  - Ra (Box 8, Folder 7)
  - Re (Box 8, Folder 8)
  - Ri-Ric (Box 8, Folder 9)
  - Rim (Box 8, Folder 10)
  - Ro, T. (Box 8, Folder 11)
  - Roe (Box 8, Folder 12)
  - Sa (Box 8, Folder 13)
  - Schneider (Box 8, Folder 14)
  - Schnut (Box 8, Folder 15)
  - Schu (Box 8, Folder 16)
  - Sh-Si (Box 8, Folder 17)
  - Sm (Box 9, Folder 1)
  - Sol (Box 9, Folder 2)
  - Sos (Box 9, Folder 3)
  - Str (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 4)
  - Str (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 5)
  - Ta (1 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 6)
  - Ta (2 of 2) (Box 9, Folder 7)
  - Tra (Box 9, Folder 8)
  - Ty (Box 9, Folder 9)
  - U (Box 9, Folder 10)
  - Ve (Box 9, Folder 11)
  - Vo (Box 9, Folder 12)
  - War (Box 9, Folder 13)
  - Wat (Box 9, Folder 14)
  - Wet (Box 10, Folder 1)
  - White (Box 10, Folder 2)
  - Whitf (Box 10, Folder 3)
  - Whitm (Box 10, Folder 4)
  - Wr-X (Box 10, Folder 5)
  - Y (Box 10, Folder 6)
- Series IV: Addenda
  - Personnel: Ballestero (Box 10, Folder 7)
  - Personnel: Besbris (Box 10, Folder 8)
  - Personnel: Dannemiller (Box 10, Folder 9)
  - Personnel: Disch (Box 10, Folder 10)
  - Personnel: Faubion (Box 10, Folder 11)
  - Personnel: Lane (Box 10, Folder 12)
  - Personnel: Pomerantz (Box 10, Folder 13)
  - Personnel: Rusk (Box 10, Folder 14)
  - Personnel: Shibatani (Box 10, Folder 15)
  - Personnel: Sickles (Box 10, Folder 16)
  - Personnel: Wolpin (Box 10, Folder 17)
  - Personnel: Wool (Box 10, Folder 18)